dizzed.com 2013-05-19

# 

Dizzed.com Privacy Policy 

Updated February 1, 2012 

Dizzed knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. 

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Dizzed.com ("we" or "us") on the collection, use and disclosure of your information on http://www.Dizzed.com and the related services, features, content or applications we offer (collectively, "Dizzed"). In connection with your use of Dizzed, we receive information about you from various sources, including: (i) through your Dizzed user account (your "Account"); (ii) your use of Dizzed generally; and (iii) from third party websites and services. When you use Dizzed, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, transmission, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

What Does This Privacy Policy Cover? 

This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") we gather when you are using or accessing Dizzed. This Privacy Policy also covers our treatment of any Personal Information that our business partners share with us or that we share with our business partners. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, content sources, services and applications ("Third Party Services") that you elect to access through Dizzed, or to individuals that we do not manage or employ. While we attempt to facilitate access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access. 

What Information Is Collected by Dizzed? 

The information we gather enables us to personalize, improve and continue to operate Dizzed. In connection with certain aspects of Dizzed, we may request, collect and/or display some of your Personal Information. We collect the following types of information from our users. 

Sign-In Information: 

When you create an Account or login using your Twitter and/or Facebook credentials, you will provide information that could be Personal Information, such as your username, password and email address. You acknowledge that this information may be personal to you, and by creating an account with Dizzed and providing Personal Information to us, you allow others, including us, to identify you and therefore may not be anonymous. We may use your contact information to send you information about our Services, including without limitation, notifications regarding the Services and, upon your request, email digests of content shared by those that you follow on Dizzed, Twitter, and Facebook. You may unsubscribe from these messages through your Account settings, although we regardless reserve the right to contact you when we believe it is necessary, such as for account recovery purposes. 

User Content and URL Information: 

Dizzed allows you to provide content to Dizzed, such as the ability to Dizzed and Submit collections of content and uniform resource locators ("URLs"), written descriptions of content or URLs, comments, text, images and video. We also collect and store information regarding the content in your Dizzed, Twitter, and Facebook feeds and the original URL, and associate that information with your Account. We also collect and store (i) the time and date on which the content was first voted, submitted, or shared and (ii) information on the channels through which the content was shared, e.g., to other Dizzed users, Twitter followers, and/or Facebook friends. 

We share certain information about you, such as your username, any avatar or image you elect to post, your Twitter and/or Facebook username, your reading feeds through Dizzed, Twitter, Facebook and other Third Party Services, and other information you elect to make public to your followers in Dizzed, your followers on Twitter, and your friends on Facebook,. This may include Personal Information, but only to the extent that you decide to share such information with others. 

We may retain content submitted by you to Dizzed indefinitely, even after you terminate your Account. 

Metrics and Analytics: 

We collect information about accesses of content curated through Dizzed. This information includes, but is not limited to: (i) the IP address and physical location of the devices accessing the curated content; (ii) the time and date of each access; and (iii) information about sharing of curated content. 

Information Collected From Third Party Services: 

Some features of Dizzed allow you to share your Dizzed curated content through Third Party Services and your content from Third Party Services through Dizzed. If you choose to connect Dizzed to such Third Party Services, we may collect information related to your use of those Third Party Services, such as authentication tokens that allow us to connect to your Third Party Service accounts. We may otherwise collect information about how you are using Dizzed to interact with those connected Third Party Services. Note that Third Party Services may have the ability to restrict the information that is provided to us. 

IP Address Information and Other Information Collected Automatically: 

We automatically receive and record information from the Dizzed application or your web browser when you interact with Dizzed, Including your IP address and cookie information. This information is used to facilitate collection of data concerning your interaction with Dizzed (e.g., what content you have clicked on). 

Generally, Dizzed automatically collects usage information, such as the number and frequency of users accessing Dizzed and various curated streams of content. We may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us and third parties authorized by us to figure out how often individuals use parts of Dizzed so that we can analyze and improve them. 

Information Collected Using Cookies: 

Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser or application when you access a website or service. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website or service you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser or Dizzed application and tell us how and when you visit and use Dizzed through the web or through an application. 

Dizzed cookies also allow us to track when you have accessed content through Dizzed. Each access is tracked using a unique identifier assigned to you in one or more cookies stored by your web browser or application and associated with Dizzed. 

Dizzed cookies do not, by themselves, contain Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information to tell us who you are. As noted, however, we do use cookies to identify that your web browser or application has accessed content through Dizzed and may associate that information with your Account if you have one. 

This Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies only and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties. We do not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer or device. For example, third party websites may set their own cookies. 

Aggregate Information: 

We collect statistical information about how people use Dizzed ("Aggregate Information"). Some of this information is derived from Personal Information, such as your location (which, in turn, can be derived from your IP address or through location based services used by your device). This statistical information is not Personal Information and cannot be tied back to you, your Account, your web browser or your Dizzed application. 

How and To Whom Is My Information Shared? 

Dizzed is designed to help you share information that you or people you choose to follow locate on the web with others. As a result, much of the information generated through Dizzed is shared publicly or with third parties. All Dizzed content is public. Your activity on the Dizzed network is public and can be distributed to anyone that follows you. We may also distribute content and feeds through an email digest to users who have elected to receive such email digests. 

Public Dizzed Activity Information: 

Much of your activity on and through Dizzed is public by default. This includes, but is not limited to: 

URLs that you have voted on or URLs submitted to Dizzed. 

URLs within your feeds from Third Party Services that you access through Dizzed and feeds from third parties that you elect to follow. 

Content that you have selected to curate on your Account, the corresponding URL(s), the time and date that content was curated, and metrics and analytics information for your curated content, as described above; and 

Aggregate non-personal information about what content you have accessed through Dizzed and associated metrics and analytics information, as described above. 

Some of this information may be associated with your Account and some of this information is publicly accessible to other Dizzed users who choose to follow your curated content. This information may still be accessible through other means, such as our API services. 

Please also remember that if you choose to provide Personal Information using certain features of Dizzed, then that information is governed by the privacy settings of those particular features and may be publicly available. Individuals reading this information may use or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge. Therefore, we urge you to think carefully about including any specific information you may deem private in content that you create or submit through Dizzed. 

Information You Elect to Share: 

In addition to reviewing this Privacy Policy, you should also review the terms of services and privacy policies of any Third Party Services that you access through Dizzed. Dizzed respects the privacy settings/ policies that you have selected with Third Party Services, and only shares information consistent with those privacy settings and policies. 

You may otherwise access Third Party Services through Dizzed, for example by accessing curated content. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these Third Party Services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding those privacy policies. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on or through Dizzed. 

User Profile Information: 

User profile information including your username, avatars or images you elect to upload and other information you enter may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within Dizzed. We will not directly reveal users' email addresses to other users. 

Aggregate Information: 

We share Aggregate Information with our partners, service providers and other persons with whom we conduct business. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners can understand how and how often people use Dizzed and their services or websites, which facilitates improving both their services and how we interface with them. In addition, these third parties may share with us non-private, aggregated or otherwise non Personal Information about you that they have independently developed or acquired. 

Information Disclosed for the Protection of Us and Others: 

We also reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as it reasonably believes is necessary to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (ii) enforce these Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect our rights, property or safety, our users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam prevention. 

Information We Share With Your Consent: 

Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information. 

Email Communications: 

If you sign up for The Daily Dizzed email via the Dizzed website or in any other Dizzed application, you will receive an email once daily summarizing popular content on Dizzed. Dizzed users that follow you will occasionally receive email digests that include information about what you have shared through Dizzed. 

Regardless of whether you decide to receive The Daily Dizzed, as part of Dizzed, you may occasionally receive from us email and other communication relating to your Account. These emails will only be sent for purposes important to Dizzed, such as password recovery. 

We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. We use this confirmation to improve our customer service. 

Is Information About Me Secure? 

Your Account information (including your Twitter and Facebook logins) is protected for your privacy and security. You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. 

We endeavor to protect Account information to ensure that it is kept private; however, we cannot guarantee the security of any Account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. 

We otherwise store all of our information, including your IP address information, using industry-standard security techniques. We do not guarantee or warrant that such techniques will prevent unauthorized access to information about you we store, Personal Information or otherwise. 

What Information of Mine Can I Access? 

You can access information associated with your Account by logging into the web version of Dizzed, or through the Dizzed application. You can adjust settings and privacy preferences through your Account settings. 

Registered and unregistered users can access all of the above information. 

How Can I Delete My Account? 

Should you ever decide to delete your Account, you may do so by visiting Dizzed.com account settings. If you terminate and delete your Account, any association between your Account and information stored by in connection with Dizzed will no longer be accessible. However, given the nature of sharing using Dizzed, any public activity on your Account prior to deletion will remain stored on our servers and will remain accessible to the public. If you would like us to remove such stored information, please send us an email at Privacy-Help { AT } Dizzed.com. 

What Choices Do I Have Regarding My Information? 

As stated previously, you can opt not to disclose certain information to us, even though it may be needed to take advantage of some Dizzed features. 

You can delete your Account or adjust your Account's privacy settings. Please note that we will need to verify that you have the authority to delete the Account, and activity generated prior to deletion will remain stored by us and may be publicly accessible. 

What Happens When There Are Changes to this Privacy Policy? 

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on or within Dizzed or sending you an email. A user is bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses Dizzed after such changes have been first posted. 

What If I Have Questions or Concerns? 

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy using Dizzed, please send us a detailed message to: Privacy-Help { AT } Dizzed.com. We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.
